Guide to the Margaret S. Mahler Psychiatric Research Foundation Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Normal Separation-Individuation Studies, 1959-1977; Series II; 54.5 linear feet (67 boxes)
  This series contains applications, family, and medical histories, observations, personality tests, and lists of children participants in the studies of normal separation-individuation conducted by Mahler and her co-workers from 1959-1969, and follow up studies conducted by John McDevitt during the 1970s. Data from the studies beginning in 1959 contains birth and general information about the children, consent forms, releases, observations and test results arranged alphabetically by the first name of the child. Data from subsequent studies is arranged by type of material and includes categories and ratings of the children by the research staff, reduced data for specific developmental stages, notes from film observations, research notebooks maintained for each child including observations, film notes, general information, follow-up summaries, and information about the mothers. Duplicate information found in the early and later studies is also located in this series. Materials documenting the methodology for the studies devised by Fred Pine, data from the follow-up studies conducted by John McDevitt from 1970-1977, as well as research conference minutes and testing schedules are also included in this series. In addition, microfiche sets of area observations, film notes, reduced data, narratives and general remarks of the children are also included in this series.
  - Forms, 1963-1966
    - Birth Information, 1966
      - General (Box 12, Folder 211)
      - A (Box 12, Folder 212)
      - Ca (Box 12, Folder 213)
      - Co (Box 12, Folder 214)
      - E., Evan (Box 12, Folder 215)
      - E., Scott (Box 12, Folder 216)
      - J (Box 12, Folder 217)
      - Sc (Box 12, Folder 218)
      - Sh, W (Box 12, Folder 219)
    - Child's History
      - An, Au (Box 12, Folder 220)
      - C, E, J (Box 12, Folder 221)
      - Sc, Sh (Box 12, Folder 222)
      - Consent/Release, 1963 January - 1965 October (Box 12, Folder 223)
  - Early Children
    - Classification of mothers, 1962, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 224)
    - Daily log, 1964 May - 1965 June (Box 12, Folder 225-226)
    - Daily log, 1965 September - 1966 October (Box 12, Folder 227-228)
    - Group observations-A, 1959 October-November (Box 13, Folder 229)
    - Group observations-B, 1959 November - 1960 February (Box 13, Folder 230-231)
    - Group observations-C, 1960 February-June (Box 13, Folder 232)
    - Group observations-A, 1960 September-October (Box 13, Folder 233)
    - Group observations-B, 1960 November - 1961 February (Box 13, Folder 234)
    - Group observations-C, 1961 March-June (Box 13, Folder 235)
    - Notes, 1959-1961, 1964, undated (Box 13, Folder 236)
    - Observations, 1959-1965
      - Adam L., 1959 December - 1961 February (Box 13, Folder 237)
      - Alexander C., 1963 January - 1964 February (Box 13, Folder 238)
      - Amy C., 1964 October - 1965 April (Box 13, Folder 239-240)
        - Film notes, 1964 October- 1965 April (Box 13, Folder 241)
        - Follow-up, 1965 December (Box 13, Folder 242)
      - Christopher H, 1961 May- 1962 June, 1962 September - 1963 June (Box 13, Folder 243-245)
      - David S., 1961 February - 1963 May
        - Ratings, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 249)
        - Follow-up, 1963 September- 1964 April (Box 14, Folder 250)
      - Elizabeth V., 1959 November - 1960 March (Box 14, Folder 251)
      - Faith F., 1959 October - 1960 March (Box 14, Folder 252)
      - Frederick S., 1963 November - 1964 June (Box 14, Folder 253)
        - film notes, 1963 October - 1964 September (Box 14, Folder 254)
      - Gillian S., 1965 November -1967 June (Box 14, Folder 255-257)
      - Jonathan B., 1959 October - 1960 January (Box 14, Folder 258)
      - Kevin P., 1959 September - 1960 June (Box 14, Folder 259)
      - Liza B., 1960 September - 1961 March (Box 14, Folder 260)
      - Matthew D., 1959 June - 1960 April (Box 14, Folder 261)
      - Mindy S., 1959 October - 1961 May (Box 14, Folder 262)
      - Victoria L., 1959 April - 1960 June (Box 15, Folder 263)
      - Vivian H., 1963 September-December (Box 15, Folder 264)
      - Elizabeth v., 1961 January-March (Box 15, Folder 265)
      - Nellie K., 1961 February-March (Box 15, Folder 265)
      - Rachel M., 1960 October (Box 15, Folder 265)
      - Debbie P., 1961 May (Box 15, Folder 265)
    - Personality and family histories, undated (Box 15, Folder 266)
    - Study participants, 1959-1968 (Box 15, Folder 267)
    - Tests
      - Adam L., 1960 January-March (Box 15, Folder 268)
      - Amy C., 1964 (Box 15, Folder 269)
      - Christopher H., 1962 April-November (Box 15, Folder 270)
      - David S., 1961 February - 1962 November (Box 15, Folder 271)
      - Elizabeth V., 1960 January (Box 15, Folder 272)
      - Frederick S., 1964 June (Box 15, Folder 273)
      - Mindy S., 1960 January - 1961 February (Box 15, Folder 274)
      - Vivian H., 1963 October (Box 15, Folder 275)
  - Categories
    - Forms, undated (Box 15, Folder 275a)
    - Amanda I-IX, XI, XII, 1962 September - 1965 May (Box 15, Folder 276-286)
    - Amanda XIII-XVIII, 1962 September - 1965 May (Box 16, Folder 287-292)
    - Amy CL. I-XVIII, 1964 November - 1965 April (Box 16, Folder 293-294)
    - Amy Co.-abstracts, 1963 Jan, 1965 June (Box 16, Folder 295)
    - Amy Co. I-XIII, 1963 January - 1965 May (Box 16, Folder 296-307)
    - Amy Co. XIV-XVIII, 1963 January - 1965 May (Box 17, Folder 308-312)
    - Claudia I-VIII, 1966 January - 1967 June (Box 17, Folder 313-325)
    - Claudia XI-XVII, 1966 January - 1967 June (Box 18, Folder 326-333)
    - Claudia-abstract, 1966 June-December (Box 18, Folder 334)
    - Claudia-summaries, 1966 February - 1967 June (Box 18, Folder 335)
    - Debbie I-VI(A), 1965 January - 1967 June (Box 18, Folder 336-342)
    - Debbie VII-XVIII, 1965 January - 1967 June (Box 19, Folder 343-354)
    - Debbie-abstracts, 1965 February - 1966 March (Box 19, Folder 355)
    - Debbie-summaries, 1965 January - 1966 June (Box 19, Folder 356)
    - Gillian I-III, 1965 November - 1967 June (Box 19, Folder 357-359)
    - Gillian IV-IX, XI-XII, XV-XVIII, 1965 November - 1967 June (Box 20, Folder 360-373)
    - Gillian-summaries, 1965 November - 1967 June (Box 20, Folder 374)
    - Hadley I-IX, XI, 1964 October - 1967 June (Box 20, Folder 375-385)
    - Hadley XII-XVIII, 1964 October - 1967 June (Box 21, Folder 386-392)
    - Hadley-summary, 1966 January - 1967 June (Box 21, Folder 393)
    - Sylvia I-IX, 1964 October - 1967 June (Box 21, Folder 394-403)
    - Sylvia XI-XVIII, 1964 October - 1967 June (Box 22, Folder 404-411)
    - Chris A. I-IX, XI-XIII, 1963 September - 1965 June (Box 22, Folder 412-424)
    - Chris A. XIV-XVIII, 1963 September - 1965 June (Box 23, Folder 425-429)
    - Christopher H.-all, 1961 May - 1963 May (Box 23, Folder 430)
    - Evan I-XVII, 1966 March - 1967 June (Box 23, Folder 431-447)
    - Malcom I-XVIII, 1962 September - 1965 April (Box 24, Folder 448-465)
    - Michael I-V, 1965 September - 1967 June (Box 24, Folder 466-470)
    - Michael VI-IX, XI-XVII, 1965 September - 1967 June (Box 25, Folder 471-481)
    - Michael-summary, 1965 September - 1967 June (Box 25, Folder 482)
    - Paul I-IV, 1964 October - 1967 June (Box 25, Folder 483-486)
    - Paul V-IX, XI-XVIII, 1964 October - 1967 June (Box 26, Folder 487-501)
    - Paul-abstracts, 1964 October - 1966 June (Box 27, Folder 502-504)
    - Paul-summary, 1966 February-June (Box 27, Folder 505)
    - Scott I-IX, XI-XVI, 1963 September - 1966 January (Box 27, Folder 506-521)
    - Scott XVII-XVIII, 1963 September - 1966 January (Box 28, Folder 522-523)
    - Brian I-XVII, 1963 January - 1964 May (Box 28, Folder 524-525)
    - Benjamin I-XVIII, 1963 September - 1966 January (Box 28, Folder 526-544)
    - Thomas I-II, 1964 November - 1967 June (Box 28, Folder 545-546)
    - Thomas III-IX, XI-XVI, 1964 November - 1967 June (Box 29, Folder 547-563)
    - Thomas XVII-XVIII, 1964 November - 1967 June (Box 30, Folder 564-565)
    - Thomas-summary, 1966 February-October (Box 30, Folder 566)
    - Frederick I-XVII, 1963 November - 1964 June (Box 30, Folder 567)
    - Manual of monthly data collection, undated (Box 30, Folder 568)
    - Indexing, 1965 September - 1966 June (Box 30, Folder 569-571)
    - Indexing of research material, undated (Box 30, Folder 572-573)
  - Ratings
    - Observational forms, 1962, undated (Box 30, Folder 574)
    - Behavioral forms, 1962, undated (Box 30, Folder 575)
    - Completed-areas 1-3; round 1, 1961-1962 (Box 30, Folder 576-578)
    - Completed-areas 4, 5; round 1, 1961-1962 (Box 31, Folder 579-580)
    - Completed-areas 1-5; round 2, 1962 (Box 31, Folder 581-585)
    - Master sheets; round 2, 1962 (Box 31, Folder 586)
    - Random ratings, 1963 (Box 31, Folder 587)
    - Joint-areas 1 and 2-5 toddlers, 1962, 1963 (Box 31, Folder 588-589)
    - Summaries, 1962, 1964 (Box 31, Folder 590)
    - Symbiotic children, 1962 (Box 31, Folder 591)
    - Mothers, 1962 (Box 31, Folder 592)
  - Reduced Data
    - General remarks and narrative
      - 5-13 months, 1968, 1969 (Box 32, Folder 593)
      - 13-17 months, 1968, 1969 (Box 32, Folder 594)
      - 17-21 months, 1969 (Box 32, Folder 595)
      - 21-24 months, 1969 (Box 32, Folder 596)
      - 5-20 months, 1968, 1969 (Box 32, Folder 597)
    - Aggression and psychosexual development
      - 5-10 months (Box 32, Folder 598)
      - 10-18 months, 1969 (Box 32, Folder 599)
      - 18-24 months, 1969 (Box 33, Folder 600)
      - 16-21 months, 1969 (Box 33, Folder 601)
    - Moods
      - 5-10 months, 1968, 1969 (Box 33, Folder 602)
      - 10-17 months, 1969 (Box 33, Folder 603)
      - 5-17 months, 1968, 1969 (Box 33, Folder 604)
      - By subphase, undated (Box 33, Folder 605)
    - Object relations
      - 5-15 months, 1968, 1969 (Box 33, Folder 606-607)
      - 15-21 months, 1969 (Box 33, Folder 608)
      - 15-24 months, 1969 (Box 34, Folder 609)
    - Perceptual-cognitive-language development
      - 5-15 months, 1968, 1969 (Box 34, Folder 610)
      - 15-19 months, 1969 (Box 34, Folder 611)
      - 19-24 months, 1969 (Box 34, Folder 612)
      - 14-24 months, 1969 (Box 34, Folder 613)
    - Brief statements
      - Chris A., 5-20 months, 1968, 1969 (Box 34, Folder 614)
      - Paul C., 5-23 months, 1968, 1969 (Box 34, Folder 615)
      - Evan E., 1966-1967 (Box 34, Folder 616)
      - Michael S., 5-20 months, 1968, 1969 (Box 34, Folder 617)
    - Key statements
      - 4-10 months, 1967-1969 (Box 34, Folder 618)
      - Scott E., 3.5-20 months, 1968, 1969 (Box 34, Folder 619)
    - Brief statement
      - "The Danger Situation, 0-8 months, 1968, 1969 (Box 34, Folder 620)
      - "The Self, 0-8 Months", 1968, 1969 (Box 34, Folder 621)
  - Film Observations
    - "Checking Back", 1963-1967 (Box 35, Folder 622-623)
    - "Development of Locomotion", undated (Box 35, Folder 624)
    - "Early Fantasy Activity", undated (Box 35, Folder 625)
    - "Early Feeding and Weaning", undated (Box 35, Folder 626)
    - "Ego Functions", 1966 November (Box 35, Folder 627)
    - "Separation Reactions", 1963-1967, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 628)
    - Selected film sequences, 1964-1968 (Box 35, Folder 629-630)
  - Notebooks
    - Claire A. # 1-6
      - Once only material, undated (Box 35, Folder 631)
      - Observations, 1961-1963 (Box 36, Folder 632)
      - Follow-up and summary, 1963-1966 (Box 36, Folder 633)
      - Mother's book I-III, 1961-1972 (Box 36, Folder 634-636)
    - Claudia C. # 7-20
      - Once only material, undated (Box 36, Folder 637)
      - Observations I, 1965, 1966 (Box 36, Folder 638)
      - Observations II, III, 1966, 1967 (Box 37, Folder 639-640)
      - Observations IV, I, II, 1966-1968 (Box 37, Folder 641-643)
      - Ten questions I (key statements), 1965-1967 (Box 37, Folder 644)
      - Ten questions II(key statements), 1967 (Box 38, Folder 645)
      - Four topics, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 646)
      - Stranger, sleep, separation, mirror reactions, 1966, 1967 (Box 38, Folder 647)
      - Follow-up and summaries, 1968-1977 (Box 38, Folder 648-649)
      - Mrs. C.-Tests and interviews, 1966-1968 (Box 38, Folder 650)
      - Mrs. C.-Mother classification, 1966 (Box 38, Folder 651)
    - Amy C. # 21-28
      - Once only material, undated (Box 39, Folder 652)
      - Observations I-V, 1963-1965 (Box 39, Folder 653-657)
      - Intervening follow-up, 1965-1968 (Box 40, Folder 658)
      - Follow-up and summaries, 1966-1973 (Box 40, Folder 659)
    - Sylvia C. # 29-45
      - Once only material, undated (Box 40, Folder 660)
      - Observations I-IV, 1964-1967 (Box 40, Folder 661-665)
      - Area observations, 1965-1967 (Box 41, Folder 666)
      - Ten Questions (key statements), 1965-1967 (Box 41, Folder 667-668)
      - Four topics (brief statements), 1968, 1969 (Box 41, Folder 669-670)
      - Intervening follow-up and play sessions, 1967-1969 (Box 41, Folder 671)
      - Follow-up and summaries, 1967-1973 (Box 41, Folder 672)
      - Separation, sleep, stranger, mirror reaction, undated (Box 42, Folder 673)
      - Mrs. C.-Mother's book I-III, 1963-1968 (Box 42, Folder 674-676)
      - Mrs. C.-Mother's classification (Amy), undated (Box 42, Folder 677)
      - Mrs. C.-Mother's classification (Sylvia), undated (Box 42, Folder 678)
    - Jonathan A. # 46-50
      - Once only material, undated (Box 42, Folder 679)
      - Observations, 1961-1963 (Box 42, Folder 680)
      - Interim material, 1963-1968 (Box 43, Folder 681)
      - Four topics (brief statements), 1975 (Box 43, Folder 682)
      - Follow-up and summaries, 1966-1976 (Box 43, Folder 683)
    - Brian C. # 51-55
      - Once only material, undated (Box 43, Folder 684-685)
      - Observations I, II, 1962-1964 (Box 43, Folder 686-687)
      - Follow-up, 1964, 1965 (Box 44, Folder 688)
      - Mother's book, undated (Box 44, Folder 689)
    - Billy N. # 56-58
      - Once only material, undated (Box 44, Folder 690)
      - Observations, 1961-1963 (Box 44, Folder 691)
      - Follow-up and summaries, 1972, 1973 (Box 44, Folder 692)
    - Deborah J. # 59-73
      - Once only material, undated (Box 44, Folder 693)
      - Observations I, II, 1965 (Box 44, Folder 694-695)
      - Observations II, III, 1965-1967 (Box 45, Folder 696-702)
      - Observations III, 1966, 1967 (Box 46, Folder 703-704)
      - Area observations, 1965-1967 (Box 46, Folder 705)
      - Home visits, play sessions, 1966, 1967 (Box 46, Folder 706)
      - Ten questions (key statements), 1965, 1966 (Box 46, Folder 707-710)
      - Four questions (brief statements), 1968, 1969 (Box 47, Folder 711-712)
      - Stranger, sleep, separation, and mirror reactions, 1965-1967 (Box 47, Folder 713)
      - Intervening follow-up, 1967-1969 (Box 47, Folder 714)
      - Follow-up and summaries, 1973, 1974 (Box 47, Folder 715)
      - Mrs. J.-Mother's book, 1965-1967 (Box 47, Folder 716-717)
      - Mrs. J.-Mother's classification, 1965, 1966 (Box 47, Folder 718)
    - Jennifer and Helen L. # 74-80A
      - Once only material, undated (Box 48, Folder 719-720)
      - Observations I-III, 1961-1963 (Box 48, Folder 721-724)
      - Follow-up, 1965-1974 (Box 48, Folder 725)
      - Mrs. L.-Mother's book and classification, 1962, 1963 (Box 48, Folder 726)
      - Mrs. L.-Summary (Helen), 1979 (Box 49, Folder 727-728)
    - Amanda N. # 81-86
      - Once only material, undated (Box 49, Folder 729)
      - Observations I, II, 1962-1965 (Box 49, Folder 730-734)
      - Observations III, 1965 (Box 50, Folder 735)
      - Intervening follow-up, 1966-1973 (Box 50, Folder 736)
      - Mrs. N.-Mother's book, 1963-1965 (Box 50, Folder 737)
    - Susan S. # 87-90
      - Once only material, undated (Box 50, Folder 738)
      - Observations, 1961-1963 (Box 50, Folder 739-740)
      - Intervening follow-up, 1963-1978 (Box 50, Folder 741-742)
      - Mother's book, 1967 (Box 51, Folder 743)
    - Hadley S. # 91-102
      - Once only material, undated (Box 51, Folder 744)
      - Observations I-IV, 1964-1967 (Box 51, Folder 745-749)
      - Area observations, 1965-1967 (Box 52, Folder 750)
      - Four topics (brief statements), 1968, 1969 (Box 52, Folder 751-752)
      - Ten questions (key statements), 1964-1973 (Box 52, Folder 753-755)
      - Stranger, sleep, separation and mirror reactions, undated (Box 52, Folder 756)
      - Follow-up and summaries, 1973, 1974 (Box 53, Folder 757)
      - Mrs. S.-Mother's book, 1965, 1966 (Box 53, Folder 758)
    - Scott E. # 103-116
      - Once only material, undated (Box 53, Folder 759)
      - Observations I-III, 1963-1965 (Box 53, Folder 760-762)
      - Observations IV, 1965, 1966 (Box 54, Folder 763)
      - Area observations and coordinated observations, 1964-1966 (Box 54, Folder 764-765)
      - Four topics (brief statement), 1968, 1969 (Box 54, Folder 766-769)
      - Ten Questions I (key statements), 1963, 1964 (Box 54, Folder 770-771)
      - Ten questions II (key statements), 1964, 1965 (Box 55, Folder 772-773)
      - Separation, sleep, stranger, and mirror reactions, 1964, 1965 (Box 55, Folder 774-775)
      - Follow-up and summaries, 1966-1973 (Box 55, Folder 776-777)
      - Mrs. E.-Mother's book, 1963-1967 (Box 55, Folder 778)
      - Mother's classification, 1964-1966 (Box 55, Folder 779)
    - Paul C. # 117-133
      - Once only material, undated (Box 56, Folder 780)
      - Observations I-V, 1964-1967 (Box 56, Folder 781-785)
      - Area Observations I, II, 1964-1967 (Box 56, Folder 786-787)
      - Ten questions (key statements), 1965-1967 (Box 56, Folder 788-789)
      - Four topics (brief statement), 1968, 1969 (Box 56, Folder 790)
      - Separation, sleep, stranger and mirror reactions, 1964, 1965 (Box 57, Folder 791)
      - Interim material (including play sessions), 1967-1969 (Box 57, Folder 792)
      - Follow-up and summaries, 1969-1977 (Box 57, Folder 793)
      - Mrs. C.-Mother's book, 1964-1968 (Box 57, Folder 794-795)
      - Mrs. C.-Mother's classification, 1965-1967 (Box 57, Folder 796)
    - Evan E. # 134-139
      - Once only material, undated (Box 57, Folder 797)
      - Observations I, II, 1966-1968 (Box 57, Folder 798-799)
      - Area observations, 1966, 1967 (Box 57, Folder 800)
      - Follow-up and summaries, 1968-1973 (Box 57, Folder 801)
      - Mrs. E.-Mother's book, 1966, 1967 (Box 57, Folder 802)
    - Michael S. # 140-153
      - Once only material, undated (Box 57, Folder 803)
      - Observations I, 1965, 1966 (Box 57, Folder 804)
      - Observations II-IV, 1966, 1967 (Box 58, Folder 805-807)
      - Area Observations I, II, 1965-1967 (Box 58, Folder 808-809)
      - Four topics (brief statements), 1968, 1969 (Box 58, Folder 810)
      - Ten questions (key statements), 1965-1967 (Box 58, Folder 811-812)
      - Separation, sleep, stranger and mirror reaction, 1965, 1966 (Box 58, Folder 813)
      - Follow-up and summaries, 1967, 1973 (Box 58, Folder 814)
      - Mrs. S.-Mother's book, 1965-1967 (Box 58, Folder 815)
      - Mrs. S.-Mother's classification, 1967 (Box 58, Folder 816)
    - Malcolm S. # 154-159
      - Once only material, undated (Box 58, Folder 817)
      - Observations I-III, 1962-1965 (Box 59, Folder 818-820)
      - Follow-up, 1965-1967 (Box 59, Folder 821)
      - Mrs. S.-Mother's book, 1962-1965 (Box 59, Folder 822)
    - Christopher A. # 160-172
      - Follow-up and summaries, 1966-1974 (Box 59, Folder 823)
      - Once only material, undated (Box 59, Folder 824)
      - Observations I-IV, 1963-1965 (Box 59, Folder 825-828)
      - Observations V, 1965, 1966 (Box 60, Folder 829)
      - Area observations and coordinated observations, 1963-1966 (Box 60, Folder 830)
      - Ten questions (key statements), 1964, 1965 (Box 60, Folder 831-832)
      - Four topics (brief statement, 1968, 1969 (Box 60, Folder 833)
      - Separation, sleep, stranger and mirror reactions, 1963, 1964 (Box 60, Folder 834)
      - Mother's classification, 1967 (Box 60, Folder 835)
    - Benjamin A. # 173-180
      - Once only material, undated (Box 60, Folder 836)
      - Observations I-III, 1963-1965 (Box 60, Folder 837-839)
      - Observations IV, 1965, 1966 (Box 61, Folder 840)
      - Area observations, 1964-1966 (Box 61, Folder 841)
      - Follow-up and summaries, 1968-1973 (Box 61, Folder 842)
      - Mrs. A.-Mother's book, 1962-1965 (Box 61, Folder 843)
    - Tommy A. # 181-196
      - Once only material, undated (Box 61, Folder 844)
      - Observations I-V, 1964-1967 (Box 61, Folder 845-849)
      - Area observations and coordinated observations, 1965-1967 (Box 61, Folder 850-851)
      - Separation, sleep, stranger and mirror reactions, 1965, 1966 (Box 61, Folder 852)
      - Four topics (brief statements), 1968, 1969 (Box 62, Folder 853)
      - Ten questions (key statements), 1965, 1966 (Box 62, Folder 854-855)
      - Interim follow-up, 1967, 1968 (Box 62, Folder 856)
      - Follow-up and summaries, 1967, 1973 (Box 62, Folder 857)
      - Mrs. A. - Mother's book (Box 62, Folder 858)
        General
        See also: box 60, folder 835
      - Group observations I, II, 1961-1963 (Box 62, Folder 859-861)
    - # 197-227
      - Film notes, birth-15 months, undated (Box 63, Folder 862-868)
      - Film notes, 16-26 months, undated (Box 64, Folder 869-873)
      - Film conferences Film guide with frame numbers, 1968, 1969 (Box 64, Folder 874)
      - Staff and research conference minutes, 1959-1963 (Box 64, Folder 875)
      - Staff and research conference minutes, 1963-1966 (Box 65, Folder 876-883)
      - Staff and research conference minutes, 1966-1968 (Box 66, Folder 884-892)
      - Staff and research conference minutes, 1968-1976 (Box 67, Folder 893-897)
  - Early Children Folders
    - Observations
    - Fl: Amy C., 1964, 1965 (Box 67, Folder 898)
    - F2-F4: Amy C., 1964, 1965 (Box 68, Folder 899)
      film notes
    - F5-F9: David S. ratings, follow-up, 1960-1964 (Box 68, Folder 900)
    - F10-F12: Christopher H., 1961-1963 (Box 68, Folder 901)
    - F13-F14: Frederic, 1963, 1964 (Box 68, Folder 902)
    - F15-F18: Gillian, 1966, 1967 (Box 68, Folder 903)
    - F19: Adam, 1959-1961 (Box 68, Folder 904)
      summaries
    - F20: Vivian, 1965 (Box 68, Folder 905)
    - F21: Victoria L., 1959, 1960 (Box 68, Folder 906)
    - F22: Mindy S., 1959-1961 (Box 68, Folder 907)
    - F23: Matthew D; Liza, 1959-1961 (Box 68, Folder 908)
    - F24: Faith; Elizabeth, 1959, 1960 (Box 68, Folder 909)
    - F25: Peter K., 1958-1960 (Box 68, Folder 910)
    - F26: Jonathan B., 1959, 1960 (Box 68, Folder 911)
    - F27: Elizabeth V.; Nellie K.; Rachel M.; Debbie P., 1959, 1960 (Box 68, Folder 912)
    - F28-F33: Group observations A-C, 1959-1961 (Box 68, Folder 913-914)
    - F34: Tests; classification of mothers, 1962, 1963 (Box 68, Folder 915)
    - F35-F42: Tests-Adam, Amy, Christopher H., David, Elizabeth V., Frederic, Mindy, Vivian, 1960-1962 (Box 68, Folder 916)
  - Duplicate Notebook Material
    - Group observation, 1964-1967, n. d. (Box 69, Folder 917)
    - Alex C.-Observations, follow-up, 1965, 1966 (Box 69, Folder 918)
    - Amanda N.
      - Once only material, undated (Box 69, Folder 919)
      - Observations, 1965, 1966 (Box 69, Folder 920)
      - Follow-up and summaries, 1973 (Box 69, Folder 921)
    - Amy Cl.-Once only material, undated (Box 69, Folder 922)
    - Amy Co.
      - Once only material, undated (Box 69, Folder 923)
      - Observations, 1963 (Box 69, Folder 924)
      - Follow-up and summaries, 1973 (Box 69, Folder 925)
    - Benjamin A.
      - Once only material, undated (Box 69, Folder 926)
      - Follow-up and summaries, 1963-1966, 1973 (Box 69, Folder 927)
    - Billy N.
      - Once only material, undated (Box 69, Folder 928)
      - Four topics, 1975 (Box 69, Folder 929)